Ryan S. Brown

Contact

2554 Nathaniel Rochester Hall

Rochester, NY 14623

(323) 761-9146 sb@ryansb.com

OBJECTIVE

Seeking full time employment in the design and implementation of cloud systems in a DevOps or Software Engineering role. Available May of 2013.

Summary

I love working with large systems, the less predictable the better. Building a system that may have to deal with fifteen times the traffic or multiple failures is my favorite kind of project. My free time quickly fills with personal projects and time spent researching new tools or areas of my field.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology – Rochester, NY

September 2009 – Present

- Major: B.S. Applied Networking and Systems Administration
- GPA: 3.4
- Minor: Software EngineeringExpected graduation: May 2013

EXPERIENCE

RIT Lab for Technological Literacy - Rochester, NY

August 2012 – Present

System Administrator

http://foss.rit.edu/

Worked as a System Administrator in the Free and Open Source Software initiative under the Lab For Technological Literacy. Maintained user-facing web applications and services while configuring new ones.

Rochester Institute of Technology – Rochester, NY

August 2011 – Present

Resident Advisor

http://reslife.rit.edu/

Mentored and supervised 55 co-ed students ranging from first to fifth year. Duties also included planning and hosting community building events, enforcing policies, and resolving conflicts between residents.

Google – Pittsburgh, PA

June – August 2012

Software Engineer Intern

http://google.com/

Wrote infrastructure management software in Python and C++. This required a deep familiarity with Google compute resources and infrastructure to understand the project scope. The software managed requests for maintenance-related downtime and scheduled them as to not interfere with running services or unnecessarily impact redundancy.

Cypherworx, Inc. - Fairport, NY

March – June 2012

Cloud Infrastructure Consultant

http://cypherworx.com/

Worked to design a scalable infrastructure on Rackspace that would cope with their growing user base. Wrote maintenance scripts for the new instances in Bash and Python, as well as tools to move existing content Rackspace's CDN without changing existing workflows.

Newstex, LLC - Telecommute

 $March\ 2011-March\ 2012$

Application Support Engineer

http://newstex.com/

Wrote WSGI applications to deliver news stories to customers. Also developed applications that interacted with Amazon Web Services including EC2, S3, SQS, Route53, and SDB. Primary role was the design and implementation of RESTful API's that were part of a set of internal tools that parsed XHTML/XML with absolutely minimal delay.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python, C++, Perl, Java, Bash, PHP, SASS/CSS

Platforms Linux [RHEL, CentOS, Debian], Windows Server [2008, 2003], Z/OS

Services Kerberos, BIND, DHCPD, Apache, NginX, Jabber

Tools Vim, Git, Mercurial, Regex, Make, Nose, LATEX

PROJECTS

Boto: Contributed to the open-source Python interface to Amazon Web Services, added support for uploading and executing scripts automatically on new instances. http://github.com/boto/boto/

IMPULSE Shell: Wrote a Python shell to interface to IMPULSE, a PgSQL-backed application to manage DNS, DHCP, and network resources. The shell allowed users to interactively make changes in the PgSQL backend their devices, addresses, and DNS records. http://github.com/ryansb/ish/